<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Tushar Singh</title>
    <link>https://tusharsingh62.github.io/portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Tushar Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 11:15:58 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tusharsingh62.github.io/portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 5: End-to-End development of Machine Learning Heart Failure Prediction model</title>
      <link>https://tusharsingh62.github.io/portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tusharsingh62.github.io/portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Full Implementation and Web Application Link  WebApp deployed using Heroku Source code on GitHub Jupyter Notebook  Steps Involved  Data Collection Data Cleaning Exploratory data analysis Model Building Hyperparameter Tuning Best model selection Model deployed on production environment  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Proof statistically that unsupervised representation learning enhance classifier performance</title>
      <link>https://tusharsingh62.github.io/portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tusharsingh62.github.io/portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Full Implementation and details  Project on GitHub  Problem Statement Design and train a network that combines supervised and unsupervised architecture in one model to achieve a classification task
Dataset  Strictly Imbalance CIFAR-10 dataset  Architecture  Convolutional Neural Network based AutoEncoder Encoder architecture as classifer with additional dense layer to classify images  Handling Imbalance dataset  Proper distribution of weights for each class Data augmentation emphasize on minority classes  AutoEncoder Training Results  Reconstruction of images with Mean-Squared-Error loss  Classifier Training Scenarios Experiment Results Accuracy on CIFAR-10 test dataset on 10,000 images     Training Methodology Xavier Init Pretrained Autoencoder Init Avg Improvement     Data Augmentation SGD 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: IMDb Movies Case Study</title>
      <link>https://tusharsingh62.github.io/portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tusharsingh62.github.io/portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>We have the data for the 100 top-rated movies from the past decade along with various pieces of information about the movie, its actors, and the voters who have rated these movies online. we will try to find some interesting insights into these movies and their voters, using Python.
Full details and Implementation  Jupyter Notebook  Some of the interesting insights Average ratings by Males and Females varying across the genres Inferences: Sci-Fi appears to be the highest rated genre in the age group of U18 for both males and females.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Andorid play store apps analysis</title>
      <link>https://tusharsingh62.github.io/portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tusharsingh62.github.io/portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Data visualisation with the help of a case study. It enable us to understand how visualisation aids in solving business problems  Data Handling and Cleaning Techniques   Missing Values
 Dropping the rows containing the missing values Imputing the missing values Keep the missing values if they don&amp;rsquo;t affect the analysis    Incorrect Data Types
 Clean certain values Clean and convert an entire column    Sanity Checks: The data that we have needs to make sense and therefore we can perform certain sanity checks on them to ensure they are factually correct as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Churn Predictive Modeling</title>
      <link>https://tusharsingh62.github.io/portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tusharsingh62.github.io/portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Predict behavior to retain customers. We can analyze all relevant customer data and develop focused customer retention programs
Full details and Implementation  Notebook Visualisation Project on GitHub  Prediction score on several machine learning algorithms </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
